<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><chapter id="sylpheed-faq-2">
  <title>Sylpheed FAQ - Installation and Configuration</title>
  <qandaset id="faq-installation">
<?dbhtml cellspacing="13px" ?>    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>What does it take to compile Sylpheed?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Any POSIX compliant UNIX or similar OS, e.g. Linux,
FreeBSD, Solaris.
GTK+ 2.4.0 or later (GTK+ 2.6.0 or later
is recommended).
A recent ANSI C compiler (gcc 2.7.2.3 should also
work).</para>
        <note>
          <para>It is reported that Sun C will not compile
Sylpheed.</para>
        </note>
        <para>Optionally:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>compface (for X-Face)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>GPGME (for GnuPG)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>OpenSSL for SSL support</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>GtkSpell for a spell checking feature</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>cURL for allowing Sylpheed to check for updates</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>JPilot</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>LDAP</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>the equivalent of GTK+-devel and Xfree86-devel</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>you may also require flex (lex) and bison
(yacc).</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>Otherwise ./configure will fail.
See also the <filename>INSTALL</filename> file that is being distributed with the Sylpheed tarball.</para>
        <para>Note that as Sylpheed now supports the Windows platform, you can also compile it using <ulink url="http://www.mingw.org/">MinGW</ulink>.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>How do I set up Sylpheed?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>When you run Sylpheed for the first time, it will
ask you where you want to store your mailboxes. The
default is <filename>$HOME/Mail</filename> (or <filename>%APPDATA%\Sylpheed\Mailboxes\Mail</filename> under Windows). You can change this to
anything you like as long as it is a valid directory
name.</para>
        <note>
          <para>When Sylpheed is executed for the first time, it automatically creates the configuration files under <filename>$HOME/.sylpheed-2.0/</filename> (or <filename>%APPDATA%\Sylpheed\</filename> under Windows), and asks you the location of mailbox. As stated above, the default is <filename>$HOME/Mail</filename>, or <filename>%APPDATA%\Sylpheed\Mailboxes\Mail</filename> under Windows. If some files, which are non-MH format, already exist on the directory, you will have to specify another location.</para>
        </note>
        <para>Furthermore, you need to <link linkend="faq-account-setup">create at least one account</link> to be able to receive or send messages.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>Why did the creation of the mailbox fail?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Sylpheed reports such an error if it can&apos;t create the default
mailboxes (inbox, outbox, etc.). This can be because <filename>$HOME/Mail</filename>
(or <filename>%APPDATA%\Sylpheed\Mailboxes\Mail</filename> under Windows) already contains files with the same names. This occurs when switching from
Kmail to Sylpheed, in this case backup and remove the existing Mail
directory or use another name for the Sylpheed mail directory.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question id="faq-account-setup">
        <para>How do I set up an account?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>After loading Sylpheed for the first time, you can
add an email account by clicking the <guimenu>Configuration</guimenu> menu. Select the option <guimenuitem>Create new account</guimenuitem> and let the configuration assistant help you with the initial setup.
In a few easy steps, the assistant allows you to conveniently configure your  POP3, IMAP4, or Gmail account.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>If you want later to change your account configuration, just select  <menuchoice>
              <guimenuitem>Configuration</guimenuitem>
              <guimenuitem>Preferences for current account...</guimenuitem>
            </menuchoice>, or <menuchoice>
              <guimenuitem>Configuration</guimenuitem>
              <guimenuitem>Edit accounts...</guimenuitem>
            </menuchoice></para>
        </tip>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>How many accounts can I set up in Sylpheed?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>The number is unlimited. The limit is reached when
your computer stops responding.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>Can I set up an account for sending mail only?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Yes, add a new account using <menuchoice>
            <guimenuitem>Configuration</guimenuitem>
            <guimenuitem>Edit accounts...</guimenuitem>
            <guibutton>Add</guibutton>
          </menuchoice>  and set the Protocol to None (local).</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>Why does Sylpheed not delete my mails when I press &quot;Delete&quot;? I set a filter, and Sylpheed does not filter. I moved a mail to a different mailbox and it did not move.</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>You have to click the <guiicon>Execute</guiicon> button.
The other solution: in the configuration settings
(<menuchoice>
            <guimenuitem>Common preferences...</guimenuitem>
            <guimenuitem>Details</guimenuitem>
            <guimenuitem>Interface</guimenuitem>
          </menuchoice>), you have to
check the <guilabel>Execute immediately when moving or deleting messages</guilabel> box.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>Can I set up special addresses/ports for my mailserver/newsserver?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Yes, you can. Under <menuchoice>
            <guimenu>Configuration</guimenu>
            <guimenuitem>Preferences for current account...</guimenuitem>
            <guimenuitem>Advanced</guimenuitem>
          </menuchoice>, you
can specify the exact port addresses you want to use.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>Does Sylpheed have options for threading messages?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Yes. You can switch it on and off in the <guimenu>View</guimenu>
     menu, just select <guimenuitem>Thread view</guimenuitem> or press <keycombo>
            <keycap>Ctrl</keycap>
            <keycap>T</keycap>
          </keycombo>.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>Can I create multiple levels of subfolders to store mail?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Absolutely. This is no problem.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>Why isn&apos;t Sylpheed sending my mail out?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>You need to create at least one account in order to
     send. (This is a wonderful gotcha on LAN installs
     with only a local mailbox feed).</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>How do I apply a patch after downloading it?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Copy patch to sylpheed directory.
     Apply the patch as follows:</para>
        <para>
     <command>% patch -p0 &lt; some.patch</command></para>
        <para>
     Or, if it&apos;s gzipped:</para>
        <para>
     <command>% gzip -dc some.patch.gz | patch -p0</command></para>
        <para>
     Run <filename>./autogen.sh</filename>, remove the generated <filename>/config.cache</filename>
     file (unless you want to install in prefix
     <filename>/usr/local</filename>).
     Run <filename>./configure</filename> with the appropriate options and
     then <filename>make</filename>.
     (Text as found on the former Sylpheed patches page.)</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>How do I compile in support for compface pictures?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>You have to have a package called <computeroutput>libcompface</computeroutput>
     installed, so this is available for compiling into
     Sylpheed. Note that the exact name of the package depends on  OS or distribution you use.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>How do I make my own compface image?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>The faces package contains a program called xbm2ikon script,
 which converts a 48x48 xbm to the format suitable for
 compface. Thanks to Jeff Dairiki, you can have a complete online course in this. Visit <ulink url="http://www.dairiki.org/xface/">this page</ulink> for the details.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>How can I tell my browser/newsclient/other program to use Sylpheed as email program?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para> In the settings part of the program, write
       <command>sylpheed --compose</command></para>
        <para>
Specific options for typical browsers:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Opera: <command>sylpheed --compose [mailto:%t][?subject=%s] </command></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Galeon: <command>sylpheed --compose &quot;mailto:%t?subject=%s&quot;</command></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>How do I enable GPG support in Sylpheed?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para> When compiling Sylpheed, make sure you add <parameter>--enable-gpgme</parameter> in the <command>./configure</command> command.
When that completes successfully, there is a <guimenuitem>Privacy</guimenuitem> section in the <guimenuitem>Common Preferences</guimenuitem>.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>Mutt does not recognize Sylpheed&apos;s MH structure</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>For this to work you need to use the <command>touch</command> command in every MH folder. &quot;<command>touch</command>&quot; the file <filename>.xmhcache</filename> and Mutt should do just fine.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>Viewing a GIF file within Sylpheed causes a segmentation fault.</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>In case this happens, you can easily fix that by adding the following to <filename>/etc/mime.types</filename>:</para>
        <programlisting>image/gif gif</programlisting>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>How Sylpheed checks for new mail?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>New mail can be retrieved either manually or automatically.</para>
        <para>To check for new mail the manual way, you can:</para>
        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Either press the <guibutton>Get </guibutton>button on the toolbar to incorporate new mail  for the current account only, or use the <guibutton>Get all</guibutton> button to incorporate new mail for all configured accounts.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Or choose <menuchoice>
                <guimenu>File</guimenu>
                <guimenuitem>Mailbox</guimenuitem>
                <guimenuitem>Check for new messages</guimenuitem>
              </menuchoice>, or <guimenuitem>Check for new messages in all mailboxes</guimenuitem>.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Or select <menuchoice>
                <guimenu>Message</guimenu>
                <guimenuitem>Receive</guimenuitem>
                <guimenuitem>Get from current account</guimenuitem>
              </menuchoice>, or <guimenuitem>Get from all accounts</guimenuitem>.</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        <tip>
          <para>If you have a POP3 account and  don&apos;t want to retrieve all the new messages stored on  remote server to your computer, you can manage your account remotely (e.g. open or delete individual messages) by choosing <menuchoice>
              <guimenu>Message</guimenu>
              <guimenuitem>Receive</guimenuitem>
              <guimenuitem>Remote mailbox...</guimenuitem>
            </menuchoice></para>
        </tip>
        <para>If you prefer autochecking for new mail instead, first of all, make sure that you have checked <menuchoice>
            <guimenu>Configuration</guimenu>
            <guimenuitem>Common preferences...</guimenuitem>
            <guimenuitem>Receive</guimenuitem>
            <guilabel>Autocheck new mail every <replaceable>10</replaceable> minute(s)</guilabel>
          </menuchoice>. Optionally, you can adjust the interval value (in minutes) as well.</para>
        <para>Also check your settings under <menuchoice>
            <guimenu>Configuration</guimenu>
            <guimenuitem>Edit accounts...</guimenuitem>
          </menuchoice> You will find this
at the top:  <guilabel>Check the boxes on the &apos;G&apos; column to enable message retrieval by &apos;Get all&apos;</guilabel>. The setting applies on both manual  and automatic
mail checks.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>How can I make Sylpheed notify me when new mail arrives?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Download Gkrellm or a similar program that is able to notify you of new incoming mail. Gkrellm is available at <ulink url="http://www.gkrellm.net">the Gkrellm page</ulink>.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>Can I use a spell checker with Sylpheed?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Yes. You need to have GtkSpell installed prior to Sylpheed compilation. The support for GtkSpell is enabled by default in  <command>configure</command>. (If you want to disable it, make sure you add <parameter>--disable-gtkspell</parameter> in the <command>./configure</command> command.)</para>
        <para>The GtkSpell option is not supported in Sylpheed for Windows (yet), so you will have no spell checking under this OS.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>How can I make Sylpheed send my compface image in the mails?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>In the <menuchoice>
            <guimenu>Configuration</guimenu>
            <guimenuitem>Preferences for current account...</guimenuitem>
            <guimenuitem>Send</guimenuitem>
          </menuchoice> check <guilabel>Add user-defined header</guilabel> and press <guibutton>Edit</guibutton> button. A dialog appears, add a header named &quot;X-Face&quot; and fill the value field with your face data. Note that if you paste the data from a terminal into the field, some spurious newlines can be added, and these can mangle your face, be careful.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>How can I get the newest source code from the Sylpheed Subversion (SVN) repository?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Move to an appropriate directory, and after you run the command specified below, a source tree named <filename>trunk</filename> will be created under that directory:</para>
        <para><command>svn checkout svn://sylpheed.sraoss.jp/sylpheed/trunk</command></para>
        <para>The subdirectories under the <filename>sylpheed</filename> directory are  as follows:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><filename>trunk/</filename> - main tree</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><filename>branches/</filename> - miscellaneous experimental branches</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><filename>tags/</filename> - release-tagged branches</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>To update to the newest source tree, run the following command in the target directory:</para>
        <para><command>svn update</command></para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>I checked out the sources using SVN and can&apos;t find any configure script.</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>The SVN versions are meant to be used by developers rather than &quot;normal&quot;
     users, so the source (or binary) distributions are easier to use.</para>
        <blockquote>
          <para>Yeah, but the latest features from SVN really look sexy...</para>
        </blockquote>
        <para>You need to generate the configure script by running <filename>autogen.sh</filename>.
     Be sure to have autoconf and automake packages installed for this.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>Running &quot;autogen.sh&quot; gives error messages that &quot;AM_PATH_GDK_PIXBUF&quot; or
     &quot;AM_PATH_(whatever)&quot; is not found.</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>There are some <filename>*.m4</filename> files in the <filename>ac/missing</filename> directory. Try to copy
     them into the <filename>ac</filename> directory and run <filename>autogen.sh</filename> again.</para>
        <para>
     If there are still some <filename>.m4</filename> files not found (e.g. those from GTK+), try
     to run <command>% locate m4 | less</command> or <command>% locate aclocal | less</command> to find additional directories containing those macros. If you find e.g. a
     <filename>gtk.m4</filename> in <filename>/opt/gnome/share/aclocal</filename>, change following line in
     <filename>autogen.sh</filename> from</para>
        <programlisting>aclocal -I ac \</programlisting>
        <para>     to</para>
        <programlisting>aclocal -I ac -I /opt/gnome/share/aclocal \</programlisting>
        <para>and run it again.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>I don&apos;t want to compile in support for (...) any longer, but after running
     &quot;configure&quot;, those libraries are still used.</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Remove the <filename>config.cache</filename> file and run <command>./configure</command> again. You should
     also use <command>make clean</command> to avoid undefined references.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>How can I select different applications to open with specific MIME types?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>The MIME-type to application associations are kept in <filename>/etc/mailcap</filename>.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>How can I change the suggested mimetype for attachments?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>The extension to MIME-type associations are kept in <filename>/etc/mime.types</filename></para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>The folder list is not updated after I manually moved/copied folders.</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>You need to update Sylpheed cache. Right click on the mailbox and choose
     <guimenuitem>Rebuild folder tree</guimenuitem>.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>How can I revert original settings, e.g. for fonts, key bindings, etc.?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Sylpheed keeps its configuration files in <filename>$HOME/.sylpheed-2.0/sylpheedrc</filename> (or <filename>%APPDATA%\Sylpheed\sylpheedrc</filename> under Windows) and creates default
     entries, if none are found. So the easiest way is to quit Sylpheed,
     temporarily renaming your <filename>$HOME/.sylpheed-2.0</filename> (or <filename>%APPDATA%\Sylpheed\sylpheedrc</filename>) e.g. to <filename>*.bak</filename> and restarting
     Sylpheed in order to get default entries.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question id="faq-environment-variables">
        <para>What environment variables have effect on Sylpheed?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Here are the most common variables:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><envar>HOME</envar>
      - location of <filename>.sylpheed-2.0</filename> (config directory) and default folder for Mailboxes.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><envar>LANG</envar>,</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><envar>LC_ALL</envar>,</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><envar>LC_CTYPE</envar>,</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><envar>LC_MESSAGES</envar> - locale settings, e.g. language and date format.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>For more information on how to make Sylpheed display your language, see the <link linkend="faq-display-language">relevant question</link>.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>Special characters (e.g. umlauts) are not displayed correctly.</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>In most cases, this is caused by fonts that use an unsuitable encoding on a not Unicode-based system. (On a Unicode-based system, fonts should support all thinkable characters for the vast majority of languages.)</para>
        <para>Choose <menuchoice>
            <guimenu>Configuration</guimenu>
            <guimenuitem>Common preferences...</guimenuitem>
            <guimenuitem>Display</guimenuitem>
            <guimenuitem>General</guimenuitem>
          </menuchoice>, and click the button right to  <guilabel>Text font</guilabel>. Now, a special dialog appears that allows you to pick a desirable font family, style, and size.</para>
        <para>You should also make sure that your environment variables regarding locale
     settings have sensible values.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>How can I convert my old mailbox/address book from (some mail client).</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>You can  try to
     export your old mailbox to MH,  MBOX or EML format.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>Take a look at the <guimenuitem>Add sender to address book...</guimenuitem> item from the <guimenu>Tools</guimenu>
     menu, it could be a useful alternative or addition, when importing your old
     contacts.</para>
        </tip>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>What config files are there, and what are they used for?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Sylpheed config files can be found in <filename>$HOME/.sylpheed-2.0</filename> (under Windows, the path is <filename>%APPDATA%\Sylpheed</filename>). They are in plain
     text format and quite easy to understand, so don&apos;t fear to take a look
     into them using a text editor.</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><filename>sylpheedrc</filename>      - main configuration: nearly all options from the
                        settings window, e.g. mailbox location, font
                        entries, etc.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><filename>accountrc</filename>       - settings for POP/IMAP/NNTP accounts</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><filename>actionsrc</filename>       - user-defined actions</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><filename>addrbook-*.xml</filename>  - contents of your address book</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><filename>customheaderrc</filename>  - contains user-defined header lines</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><filename>dispheaderrc</filename>    - headers to display above the mail body</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><filename>filter.xml</filename>        -  filter settings</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><filename>folderlist.xml</filename>  -  folder specific settings, e.g. hiding
                        read messages, sort order, etc.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><filename>menurc</filename>          - key bindings</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>How do I change the location of user profile directory under Windows?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>The configuration files and the mailboxes are saved under the following
location (<filename>%APPDATA%\Sylpheed</filename>) by default:</para>
        <para><itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Windows 2000/XP:
<filename>C:\Documents and Settings\<replaceable>(user name)</replaceable>\Application Data\Sylpheed</filename></para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Windows Vista/Seven:
<filename>C:\Users\<replaceable>(user name)</replaceable>\AppData\Roaming\Sylpheed</filename></para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>
        <para>If you want to change the location of the configuration files, you can
specify it by the command line option <parameter>--configdir &quot;<replaceable>directory name</replaceable>&quot;</parameter>.
Create a shortcut of <filename>sylpheed.exe</filename>, and append the option to the link target
like the following:</para>
        <screen>&quot;C:\Program Files\Sylpheed\sylpheed.exe&quot; --configdir &quot;D:\Sylpheed&quot;</screen>
        <para>If <filename>sylpheed.ini</filename> file exists at the same location as <filename>sylpheed.exe</filename>, it will be
loaded at startup. With this approach, you can make Sylpheed completely portable
independent of drive letters etc., and you can install it in removable media
such as USB memory.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The installer version, and GnuPG and GPGME use registry.</para>
        </note>
        <para>The sample INI file is included in the Sylpheed for Windows installation package as <filename>sample-sylpheed.ini</filename>.
Please copy or rename it to use.
<literal>ipcport</literal> specifies the port number of socket for IPC (default is 50215).
<literal>configdir</literal> specifies the location of configuration files as a relative
path from the folder in which <filename>sylpheed.exe</filename> is located, or an absolute path.</para>
        <para>(The text above is a slightly modified excerpt from the <filename>README-win32.txt</filename> file, which you should find within the <filename>C:\Program Files\Sylpheed</filename> directory.)</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>Can I run multiple instances of Sylpheed?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Yes, Sylpheed 3.1 adds support for this often requested feature. The format of the multiple instances command is as follows:</para>
        <para><command>sylpheed --instance-id <replaceable>ID</replaceable> --configdir <replaceable>path-to-alternative-configdir</replaceable></command></para>
        <para>Default <parameter>ID</parameter> is set to <literal>sylpheed</literal>, so you can specify any other instance
<parameter>ID</parameter>. The <parameter>ID</parameter> is used for the name of unix domain
socket (under UNIX), or mutex name (under Windows). <parameter>configdir</parameter> specifies the configuration directory, i.e. the location of  configuration files you want to use with the given instance.</para>
        <warning>
          <para>Do not share same configuration directories or mailboxes across multiple instances as this may lead to an unexpected application behavior!</para>
        </warning>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>What to do when printing an email prints off the paper?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>You can use enscript for this. Use <command>enscript %s</command> to print everything on one page, or <command>enscript -U2 %s</command> for printing two logical pages on one physical page.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
  </qandaset>
</chapter>
